# （石狮市）
(Shishi City)
# （早上6点）
(6 o'clock in the morning)
# （危险动作 请勿模仿）
*DANGEROUS DO NOT IMMITATE*
# （咻～ 到了）
(Whoosh~ Arrived)
# 今天早上我们来到菜市场
We are visiting the food market this morning
# 空气还是比较凉爽的
The air is still pretty cool
# 已经有很多人开始卖海鲜了
Many people have already started selling seafood
# 走吧 我们去看看有什么好吃的
Let's go. See if there's anything good to eat
# 瞧我后面的鱼肉羹店
Look at the fish and meat stew restaurant behind me
# 真的是特别忙
It's so busy
# 今天我们就去吃一碗鱼肉羹
Today, we'll have a bowl of this fish stew
# 这些都是什么呀
What are these?
# 肉羹 鱼羹 香菇丸 拳头母 肉燕
Meat stew, fish stew, mushroom balls, "quantoumu" (pork and tendon meatball), "rouyan" (special dumpling)
# 这是福建的闽南小吃
This is what Minnan snacks in Fujian look like
# 每天都是做新鲜的
It's freshly made everyday
# 都是这种白白嫩嫩的
and always white and tender like this
# 还不到我
Not my turn yet
# 打包嘛？
To go?
# 不是 我在这吃
No. Eat in.
# 肉羹怎么卖
How much is the meat stew?
# 肉羹一斤是22元
Meat stew is 22 yuan for one jin (= 500g)
# 我要一碗饭一碗汤 在这里吃
Can I have a bowl of rice and a bowl of stew? Eat in
# 饭多少钱啊
How much is the rice?
# 一共10块钱对吧
10 yuan in total, right?
# （鱼肉羹+咸饭=10块钱）
(Fish & meat stew + salty rice = 10 yuan)
# 这个咱们要的是杂的鱼肉羹
We ordered a mixed fish and meat stew
# 是8元一碗
8 yuan for one bowl
# 这个是2元的咸饭
This is the salty rice for 2 yuan
# 我们来尝尝这个鱼肉羹
Let's have a try of this fish and meat stew
# 我是亲眼见到旁边的大姐在做这个
I witnessed how the sis made it over there
# 这里面主要是鱼肉和瘦肉（猪瘦肉）
It's mostly fish and lean pork inside
# 舀一舀啊 现在还有点烫
Scoop it. It's still a little too hot
# 白的是鱼肉 红的是瘦肉 猪肉
The white is fish. The red is meat, pork
# 哇
Wow
# 这个味道就是肉紧实 而且滑嫩
The texture of the meat is like, firm and yet tender
# 如果把它从高处丢下去
If we drop it from high above
# 应该也能弹很高
it probably bounces back high
# 这个汤表面还是飘着一些油花的
There's still a little bit of oil floating on the soup
# 咱们倒一点醋进去
Let's add some vinegar
# 解腻啊
to reduce the greasiness
# （变好吃）
(Turning tasty)
# 怎么还有点流口水呢
Why am I mouthwatering
# 你能够想象这种酸的味道在里面
As soon as you imagine the sour taste in it
# 口水就会流出来
the mouth is watered
# 带点酸的很舒服
With a bit of sourness it's such an enjoyment
# 加醋让这种酸味来的更猛烈些吧
Add some vinegar.
Let the sourness come strike harder!
# 喝口汤～
Take a sip
# 这家店也就是卖一碗肉羹一碗饭
This restaurants sells meat stew and rice only
# 不会卖其他的东西
and nothing else
# 10元钱就能吃的饱饱的
Spend just 10 yuan, and you'll be fulfilled
# （财力证明）
(Proof of assets)
# （搅成肉泥）
(Stir into mashed meat)
# 我做了20多年了
I've been working for over 20 years
# （20年手艺认证）
# 1995年就做这个了
(Certified 20 years of skills)
Started from 1995
# 一天能用肉两三百斤呢
We consume 200-300 jin of meat a day (100-150kg)
# 现在是淡季
It's the slack season now
# 刚好节日过后 生意会比较差一点
It's right after holidays, so there's less business
# 不然的话 像我们前几天都是用上千斤肉的
Otherwise... We used over 1000 jin a few days ago
# 还有这种肉包肉（猪肉包猪肉）
And there's a "meat in meat" (pork stuffed in pork)
# 外面的肉是原味的
The pork outside is of the original flavor
# 里面的肉是调过味道的
The pork stuffed inside is seasoned
# 可见塞肉馅也是需要技术的
As you see, stuffing pork also involves much technique
# 吃饱了发现旁边有一位大叔在卖姜母鸭
After the meal, we found an uncle next door selling "Jiang Mu Ya" duck pots
# 可是 我已经吃饱啦
However, I'm already full
# 走吧
Let's go
# （关注 雪鱼探店）
(Subscribe)